Nancy Cole papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Nancy Cole Papers
1947-1986
YCAL MSS 749
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.88
(13 boxes) + 2 rolls, 2 record album storage
Cole, Nancy
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William Reese Co. on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, 1987.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 15-16 (Phonograph records): Restricted Fragile Material. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Box 17 (Reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 11 (Audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Nancy Cole
Nancy Cole is an American actor who, during the 1960s and 1970s, regularly took on the persona of Gertrude Stein and performed a one-woman show, Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein, based on Stein's original writings.
Arrangement
Organized under seven headings, reflecting the order in which the material was received by the library: Files Relating to One of Each, Correspondence, Clippings and Ephemera, Subject Files, Printed Material, Rolled Posters, and Sound Recordings.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, including letters from Kay Boyle, Donald Gallup, Robert Haas, Marcel Marceau and the artist Henry Miller; photographs; clippings; printed material; sound recordings; and manuscripts relating to the production of Nancy Cole's one-woman show, Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein, and other projects, including One of Each.
Actors -- United States; American drama -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Impersonation -- Drama; Theater -- United States; Audiotapes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Actors -- United States -- 20th Century; Cole, Nancy; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946
- Files Relating to One of Each
  - One of Each: directory of items, 1965-1973 (Box 1)
  - One of Each: posters, programs, reviews, and clippings, 1958-1973; 9 (Box 1)
  - One of Each: posters, programs, reviews, and clippings, 1973-1977; 7 (Box 2)
  - One of Each: posters, programs, reviews, and clippings, 1978-1986; 6 (Box 3)
- Correspondence
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence can also be found in Subject Files.
  - A, 1972-1986 (Box 4)
  - B, 1965-1980
  - C, 1964-1980
  - D-E, 1970-1986
  - F, 1969-1983
  - G, 1964-1980
  - H, 1971-1984
  - I-K, 1964-1983 (Box 5)
  - L, 1969-1986
  - M, 1958-1980
  - N-Q, 1968-1985
  - R, 1964-1972
  - S, 1969-1982
  - T, 1968-1985
  - U-V, 1972-1974
  - W, 1959-1978
  - X-Z, 1973-1978
- Clippings and Ephemera
  Not arranged in any particular order, as received by the library.
  - Bardet, Marilyn, undated (Box 5)
  - Lupus, Gerry Garrett, 1971-1974
  - "Many Years 70's" newspaper clippings and various printed materials, 1970-1979
  - Ideas - General, newspaper clippings and various printed materials, undated
  - One of Each, from Duplicate File (under bed), newspaper clippings and various printed material, circa 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Stein clipping file, 1964-1969
  - "Courner 10", 1968
  - "Maire de Paris," invitation, 1977
- Subject Files
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent or topic.
  Files contain incoming and outgoing correspondence, notes, printed material, and photographs relating to particular individuals.
  - Baldwin, James, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Baltrusaitis, Hélène, 1965
  - Bardet, Marilyn, 1972-1973
  - Barney, Natalie C., 1965
  - Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1965
  - Barrault, Jean Louis, 1969
  - Beaton, Cecil, 1965
    Includes photographs
  - Berman, Eugene, 1965
  - Bly, Robert, 1971
  - Boyle, Kay, 1974-1979
  - Bradley, Jenny, 1965
  - Brierre, Annie, 1965
  - Brinnin, John Malcom, 1965
  - Bryher, 1965
  - Chapman, Elizabeth, 1971
  - Cleverdon, Douglas, 1968-1969
  - Cody, Morrill, 1965-1971
  - Cole, Nancy, 1965
  - Conrad, Doda, 1965
  - Crosby, Caresse, 1965 (Box 7)
  - De Beauvoir, Simòne, 1974
  - Delteil-Dudley, Caroline, 1965-1985; 2 Folders
  - Duncan, Raymond, 1965
  - Dutourd, Jean, 1965
  - Eliot, Theresa, 1965-1973
  - Eliot, T. S. (Valerie), Mrs., 1965-1969
  - Fay, Bernard, 1965
  - Fiedler, Leslie, 1972-1973
  - Finley, Ian Hamilton, undated
  - Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1972-1973
  - Fonteyn, Margot, 1965
  - Fraser, Ian Forbes, 1965
  - Fraser, Levi, Jr., 1972-1974
  - "F-G" General, 1965-1978
    Includes material relating to Bernard Frechtman, Paul Goldberger, Nadine Gordimer, Richard Gregory, Florence Gilliam and Donald Gallup.
  - Harrison, Gilbert, 1973
  - Haas, Robert Bartlett, 1971
  - Heath, Edward, 1970-1974
  - Helpmann, Robert, 1965
  - Hiler, Hilaire, 1965
  - Hughes, Langston, 1965
  - Hugo, Ian, 1970-1972
  - Jandl, Ernst, 1972-1974
  - Jolas Eugene, 1965
  - Joyce, James, 1966
  - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry, 1964-1970
  - Labauge, Marcel, 1965
  - Levin, Calman A. (Estate of Gertrude Stein), 1967-1976
  - MacGowan, Jack, 1971
  - MacLiammoir, Michael, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Manning, Mary, 1963-1973
  - Man Ray, Juliet, 1984
  - Marceau, Marcel, 1964-1973
  - Maurois, André, 1965
  - McCafferey, John, 1971-1994
  - McKenna, Siobhan, 1971
  - Miller, Henry, 1972
  - Miller, John, 1974
  - Moss, Arthur, 1965
  - Owen, Jane, 1971-1972
  - Poets' Theatre, 1967
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1965
  - Putz, François, 1973
  - Queneau, Raymond, 1965
  - Rákóczi, Basil Ivan, 1965-1977
  - Read, Herbert, 1965
  - Rogers, W. G., 1965-1971
  - Rorimer, James J., 1965
  - Rose, Francis, 1964-1965
  - Russett, Barney, 1964
  - Schneider, Douglas H., 1965
  - Seyareid, Eric, 1965-1967
  - Simpson, Helen, 1965
  - Sprigge, Elizabeth, 1964-1965
  - Stein, Julian S., Jr., 1973-1975
  - Stein, Michael, 1977-1978
  - Steloff, Frances, 1970-1971
  - Sutherland, Donald, 1965, 1973
  - Swinnerton, Frank, 1965
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1964
  - Thorndyke, Sybil, 1969
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1965-1971 (Box 9)
  - Toklas, Alice B., 1965
  - Villard, Leonie, 1965
  - Williams, Emlyn, 1969
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1965
  - Zadkine, Ossip, 1965
- Printed Material
  - One of Each: posters, programs, reviews and clippings, 1972 June-December; 6 (Box 9)
  - The World is Round, book, 1939
  - Four Americans in Paris, art collection program, 1971
  - Booklets, programs, short publications, and various printed items., 1965-1986; 3 (Box 10)
  - Les Ecrivains Américains à Paris et Leurs Amis, 1959
  - From Cole: collection Items to add, letters., undated
  - Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein, BBC programme script, 1969
  - "Four Americans in Paris Museum of Modern Art catalog, 1970
  - Saint Blaise des Simples by Jean Cocteau, 1960
  - White Pelican: Quarterly Review of the Arts, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Poète du Spectacle, Jean Cocteau, 1984
  - Façade, William Walton, undated
  - La Terre est Ronde, Gertrude Stein, 1984
  - Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein, Props, undated
  - Four Saints in Three Acts: opera score, undated
  - The Paris Metro, 1978
  - Small Posters (Box 12 (Oversize))
- Rolled Posters
  - "Originals (except Canadian)", undated (Box 13 (Roll))
  - "Printed Posters (not Canadian)", undated (Box 14 (Roll))
- Sound Recordings
  - Stein I, II and III, audio cassettes, Three audio cassettes (Box 11)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Use of original audiocassettes is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. For further information, see Access Services.
  - Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein, audio recording, undated; One phonograph record (Box 15 (Record album storage))
    Box 15 (Record Album Storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - In Circles by Gertrude Stein, music by Al Carmines; Gertrude Stein reads from her works, audio recordings, undated; One phonograph record (Box 16 (Record album storage))
    Box 16 (Record Album Storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information..
  - New Sounds for Perennial Seasons and Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein, undated; Two reel-to-reel audio tapes (Box 17)
    Box 17 (Reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.